(The tassel crowns the knight.
The sword is snow white.)
(In the silver saddle,
he rides like a shooting star.)
(He kills a man within ten steps.
Invincible he is all the way ahead.)
(He would leave once it's done.
No trace of him is to be found.)
=Sword Snow Stride= (Season 1)
=Episode 23=
(Capital of Liyang Official Posthouse)
News from Qingzhou said
your son was bold enough
to run the risks
for kidnapping Consort of Jing'an.
I heard
Lord of Jing'an
smashed his Buddhist Hall in anger.
He also hired Wang Mingyin,
No. 11 in the world,
to assassinate your son.
I'm impressed
you had Li Chungang
protect him.
Your son threatened Lord of Jing'an
with his consort,
he could do nothing except for
letting him go.
But now,
North Liang will
feud with Qingzhou.
Lots of people hate North Liang,
we can take it
if Zhao Heng does it, too.
Your son
is preposterous.
How do you feel about it?
It doesn't matter what I feel.
It matters what
His Majesty feels.
His Majesty feels pleased.
Well?
In his opinion,
such a preposterous heir
is perfect for North Liang.
Then tell me
when His Majesty
wants to see me?
Be patient.
Wait for several more days.
Your son has left Qingzhou for Yuzhou.
He'll soon arrive at
Jiangnan of Yangzhou.
Fengnian
values family and friends.
He always wants to visit his big sister.
Have you heard the news
from Jiangnan?
Staying in the capital,
my eyes are blindfolded
and my ears are covered.
How can I know anything?
It's said...
It's said that
your eldest daughter
is riotous in Jiangnan.
She has an affair with others.
The Lu Family has filed the suits
to His Majesty.
What a superb move!
Grand Commander,
you didn't notice
the hidden danger of killing.
You'll definitely lose
the game.
It's hopeless.
Do you know
what kind of player
is the most difficult?
Calculate ten steps
before he takes one step.
Seize the initiative
before his opponent does.
The player that messes up the game
is the most difficult.
It doesn't count.
Let's play another game.
It's getting late. I have to go.
You're not going.
Tell you what,
if I don't have
three straight wins today,
you're not going anywhere.
Well...
I've already made the bed for you.
Amitabha.
- Come on.
- I...
- Amitabha.
Amitabha.
(Maid Er'qiao)
Lady Zhihu.
(Eldest daughter of Lord of North Liang
Xu Zhihu)
What are you doing?
The Lu Family has a clean
and upright reputation,
not expecting it to be ruined
by such a loose woman like you.
Xu Zhihu,
rumors of you seducing men
have spread around the whole city.
You're indeed shameless.
Do you envy me?
You...
You shameless slut.
You pathetic thing.
No man wants you
even if you want to be a slut.
I must rip your mouth off.
How dare you!
Let go.
Er'qiao.
Step aside.
Let go of me.
Didn't you want to rip my mouth off?
Help yourself.
You don't think I dare to do so, do you?
I bet you dare not.
Will you do it or not?
I have a book to read.
It's a tragedy
to have such a woman like you
marry into the family.
Lady Zhihu,
the Lu Family is going too far.
Why do you still smile?
Of course I'm smiling.
I'm in a very good mood today.
My brother is coming to see me.
By my reckoning,
it takes Fengnian two more days
to arrive at Yangcheng.
(Yangcheng)
(Yangzhou Yangcheng)
Here we are.
Ask for directions to the Lu Family
after we get in.
Your Highness.
Should we wait for others
to catch up with us?
I'm going to visit my sister first.
They can meet when they arrive.
Your Highness.
What's up?
Mr. Li said he was hungry.
Sure.
It was a long journey.
We've had a long day.
No hurry.
Let's find a restaurant
and have a square meal
before we visit the Lu Family.
OK.
(Yangcheng)
(Yiding Restaurant)
Your Highness.
I've sent my men to pick up Mr. Li.
They'll arrive later.
Let's eat first.
All right.
Let's order.
Then we'll ask for directions.
Yeah. OK.
Hey, guys.
I heard
the son of Lord of North Liang
is coming to Yangcheng
to visit his elder sister.
The brother is ignorant
while the sister is shameless.
They are
the same kind of people.
I heard
Mr. Chengzhai's wife
called Xu Zhihu
a whore.
The rumors
have reached the capital.
You know what,
a concubine in the palace
is of the same clan
as Mr. Chengzhai's wife.
According to the family hierarchy,
Mr. Chengzhai's wife
is one of her nieces.
Xu Zhihu is such a dissolute woman.
How could the Lu Family
face other people?
Tell me about
the Lu Family.
I was just thinking
Xu Xiao is the kind of man
who calculates ten steps
before he takes one.
Why did he allow us
to follow Xu Fengnian?
I'm always afraid that
we'll become victims of his tricks.
Being afraid won't do you any good.
Let's wait and see first.
By the way,
why don't you take the carriage
in front of us today?
God of Sword snores heavily?
It's too noisy.
I don't understand.
The two little fellas
always jump about around me.
They seem to fear nothing.
Why are they as good and quiet
as kittens when they're around Mr. Li?
The old man is highly skilled
in martial arts.
He can keep them under control.
That is to say,
it's useful
to be skilled in martial arts.
With numerous martial artists,
West Chu was still destroyed.
That was because North Liang
was too strong.
We had the upper hand
at the beginning of the war.
I heard
many generals of Liyang were killed.
Yeah.
The legitimate son of the Lu Family
was captured
and was put to death by my father.
Which family?
The Lu Family in Yangcheng,
Xu Zhihu's husband's family?
They must bear a deep grudge
against you.
They don't know my identity.
Don't worry.
Sir.
Yeah.
What's up?
Have we got to the restaurant?
Mansion of Lu is not far.
Would you like to eat there?
It's fine.
Call me when we arrive.
Please take care of everyone
when you're at the mansion.
And
don't expose Jiang Ni's identity
to the family.
Don't you come with us?
I'm going to Jiangxin County
to meet someone surnamed Liu.
Are you going to kill him?
I'm going to figure out
what's his relationship with my sister.
Don't you know the relationship
between Mr. Liu and Xu Zhihu?
Do they have an affair?
What kind of person is Liu?
He has literary talent
and profound learning
inherited by his family.
The slut ran into him
at Baoguo Temple
and shamelessly seduced him.
He was contemptuous of her.
(Gentry of Jiangnan Liu Liting)
He simply ignored her.
Coincidentally,
(Liu Liting's wife)
Mr. Liu's wife came upon them.
Liu's wife is well connected.
It's said she is related
to a concubine in the palace.
She is Her Grace's niece.
You don't say.
How can she put up with such a slut?
Do you know what she did?
She slapped her directly in the face.
She worked off her anger.
Now everyone in Yangcheng knows
our family
have such a daughter-in-law.
It isn't true.
It was not the case.
Do you try to deny it for her?
Let's go.
People have a sense of natural justice.
Never mind.
It's natural that
being wronged and misunderstood
makes you sad.
But remember,
don't cry over it.
Tears should only
(Elegant and Refined)
be shed for your loved ones.
Remember?
Yes.
(Yangcheng of Yangzhou
Mansion of Lu)
Son of Lord of North Liang,
Xu Fengnian,
drove by Yangcheng.
Please...
I've inquired about it.
It's Liu Liting's mansion.
How's his reputation?
People say he writes good articles.
He's been talented since he was a child.
What about his family?
In Yangzhou,
his family is only regarded as
second-class.
That doesn't feel right.
What do you mean?
The Lu Family is a first-class family.
Lu Daolin, the head of the Lu Family,
is the Minister of Rites
and the principal
of the national college.
With such a status,
even Zhang Julu has to
show some respect for him.
How dare Liu Liting
hook up with the daughter-in-law
of the Lu Family?
Your Highness.
The whole city knows
it's Lady Zhihu
who has crushes on Liu.
Liu didn't hook up with her.
With my sister's status,
how can she
have crushes on such a man?
Love is not
reasonable.
Enough.
Let's find out the truth.
Shu Xiu.
I'm counting on you.
(Mansion of Lu)
Who are you?
I'm Lu Dongyang,
housekeeper of the mansion.
Nice to meet you.
Xu Fengnian,
son of Lord of North Liang,
drove by your city.
We come to visit relatives.
(No Guests) What a coincidence.
(No Guests)
We don't receive guests today.
Please go back.
Pay a visit another day.
Well,
we've just
arrived at Yangcheng.
We have no place to stay.
It's none of my business.
Would you please do us a favor
and inform Lady Zhihu?
Xu Zhihu ruined the family tradition.
How does she have the face
to receive guests?
Mr. Lu,
whatever the truth is,
please announce
our arrival.
What're you doing?
The guy humiliated us on purpose.
It has nothing to do with you.
I can't bear it.
Oh, dear.
Have you forgotten the grudge
the Lu Family held against your country?
How dare you get out?
Aren't you afraid they'll recognize you?
I was young at that time.
They won't recognize me.
It's said North Liang is a wild land.
You really know nothing about courtesy.
Didn't I make it clear?
We don't receive guests today.
Why should I notice your arrival?
Wei Shuyang is such a coward.
How could he swallow the insult?
Since Xu's daughter
married into Lu Family,
they've become allies.
Considering the relationship
between the two families,
Wei Shuyang won't be reckless.
Ouch.
Give me a blade.
How dare you!
Don't be reckless.
This...
This is Yangcheng,
not North Liang.
In North Liang,
we have a simple rule
to treat people.
If you treat me with courtesy,
I'll return you with courtesy.
If you treat me with blades,
I'll return you with those, too.
(No Guests)
Mr. Lu, please forgive her.
Open the door.
Hurry up.
Open the side door and let them in.
Open the front door.
To open the front door
requires the head's permission.
I can't make the decision.
Do you mind if I
go to ask for permission?
Don't bother.
Remove the front door.
Ah?
Give it to me.
Don't follow me.
Get back to your work.
He is Liu Liting.
Other scholars
usually keep away from the kitchen,
but he would cook himself.
It's rare.
Honey.
It's me.
My sister won't have crushes on him.
Why are you so sure?
She's got someone in her mind.
Is it her husband who died of illness?
He is at
Mount Wudang.
Mount Wudang?
Aren't there all Taoists?
Get back to your work.
Here, honey.
Try this soup.
I've cooked it for a long time.
Are you still angry?
It's bad for your health.
I'd better die of anger.
You'll find it satisfactory, won't you?
You're wrong about me.
You know
it was the slut who pestered me.
It was an unexpected calamity.
The woman is much younger than me.
Honey.
I love you truly.
How could I be attracted to that slut?
Why don't you believe me?
That woman is shameless.
Don't see her again.
I won't.
I avoid her like the plague.
How would I see her?
Taste this.
Don't be angry.
Madam hasn't started eating yet.
Come when she finishes off.
The servants become unruly now.
Don't be upset.
I'll have a look.
Who is it?
Liu Liting, Mr. Liu.
Who is this?
How dare she come to our home?
I don't know her, either.
How did you get in?
What do you want?
It tastes good.
Liu Liting.
What's going on exactly?
Honey.
Honey, cool down.
I really don't know who she is.
Who are you exactly?
How did you get in our mansion?
Get out...
Honey.
Cool down. Don't be angry.
Don't be angry.
Get someone to take her
and send her to the government.
Yes. I'm going to get help.
Madam, your hairpin is beautiful.
What do you want?
Ouch.
Miss, if you want money,
let him go.
We can talk about it.
I don't want money.
I want a life.
Mr. Liu is of a great name.
Why don't you lend me your life?
We've never met each other before.
Why do you hate me so much?
I don't hate you,
but I hate North Liang
very much.
I have nothing to do with North Liang.
Xu Zhihu
is Xu Xiao's daughter.
Then you should go to Mansion of Lu
and kill her.
The mansion is heavily guarded.
Besides,
Lu Baijie, Sword Immortal of Tangxi,
is also in the mansion.
I can't break in.
(Mansion of Lu)
It's much brighter.
Don't you think you've gone too far?
The more domineering we are,
the more relieved the royal court will feel.
If we're disciplined,
they'll fear us instead.
After all, we represent His Highness.
You shouldn't humiliate us.
Let's get inside.
Today,
it was our fault to shut you out.
I apologize
to you
on behalf of the housekeeper.
Baxiu Sword.
You are...
You're Sword Immortal of Tangxi,
Lu Baijie.
(Sword Immortal of Tangxi
Lu Baijie)
In the presence of God of Sword,
I feel unworthy of the name.
I've heard the name of God of Sword
for a long time.
Today, I venture to suggest you
show me Snakes in Sleeves.
Let's have a competition on swordplay.
How do you know he is with us?
Since the battle of Reed Marshes,
God of Sword's valorous fame
has spread throughout the world.
Sir,
would you condescend to teach me?
Qingniao.
Lady Zhihu.
Grandpa Wei.
You came so soon.
Where's Fengnian?
He went to Jiangxin County.
He's such a fool.
Uncle.
What're you doing?
Being apart for a long time,
you should catch up first.
I got it.
Lu Baijie is the only one
who regards Xu Zhihu
as a family member in the Lu Family.
It's not easy for you
to kill Xu Zhihu.
But, Miss,
you want to kill
a member of the Xu Family,
yet I'm from the Liu Family.
Everyone in Jiangnan knows that
you and Xu Zhihu are having an affair.
By killing you,
I'll let her know the taste of pain.
Miss.
Though the slut pestered my husband,
he despised her very much.
They don't have an affair.
Why don't you escape?
A wife and her husband
should live or die together.
How can I leave him?
Ouch.
You have such a good wife.
All she said is true.
I have nothing to do with Xu Zhihu.
I'm disgusted with her.
It doesn't matter
how you feel about her.
The point is she loves you.
Killing you
will make her feel pain.
Miss, spare my life.
Miss, have mercy on me.
Shut up.
Honey, help me.
Miss,
I'm related to a concubine
in the palace.
Have you thought about
the consequences?
People don't think much
while seeking revenge.
Wait. Wait.
Miss.
Let me help you to kill Xu Zhihu.
How can you do that?
The slut still has a fantasy about me.
If I ask her out,
she'll definitely come out.
Why do you tread in muddy water?
Let me write a letter
and ask her out.
Look at me.
I'm so weak.
How can I escape?
It's right.
Ouch.
Try to run away
or scream for help.
I don't think anyone would come
to rescue you.
I dare not.
Let me find a brush and some ink.
The words I'm about to say
mustn't be heard by her.
What words?
The real relationship
between Xu Zhihu and me.
(Cries of Crane)
Thank you.
Don't stand on ceremony.
I'm glad to see the people
from North Liang.
Sit down.
I've arranged accommodation
for everyone.
Don't worry.
Fengnian
should come to see me first.
His Highness
heard the rumors.
He wanted to find out the truth.
What happened between me and Liu Liting
wasn't like what people made out.
How come?
It was you who pestered Xu Zhihu?
Yes, I did.
Every time when Xu came out,
I would find a chance to run into her.
I wrote her poets
and complimented her beauty.
I used a variety of tactics
and exhausted all mental efforts.
If it were another woman,
she would be moved.
But Xu Zhihu was iron-hearted.
She always kept a good distance from me.
What about Baoguo Temple?
That mild-mannered girl
is a good mate to a gentleman.
I am
mad about you.
Your wife happened to see you?
It wasn't a coincidence.
She specially went to look for me.
And then?
She didn't see me catching her sleeves.
I kept my wits about me
and scolded Xu Zhihu
for being lack of virtue
and pestering me again and again.
You were pretty quick.
I was out of option.
What happened next?
My wife believed me.
She slapped Xu in anger.
How dare you strike me back?
You treat me with blades,
I'll return you with blades.
It's what the people of North Liang do.
So,
Xu Zhihu doesn't
have any affection for me.
The only thing she has towards me
is probably hatred.
Miss,
it won't hurt her at all
if you kill me.
I don't understand.
Since Xu was pestered by you,
why didn't she clarify the rumors?
Well,
I didn't figure it out myself.
Perhaps...
Perhaps she was
too proud
to clarify it?
Liu Liting has a literary fame
while I am
from North Liang.
People in Jiangnan
regard us as monsters.
Do you think anyone will believe me?
What about the Lu Family?
You've married into the family.
They should treat you differently.
The so-called marriage
was just a deal
made by the Lu Family and North Liang.
As soon as the deal is done,
I'm of no use.
Why do you think they let me
marry a dying man?
Lady Zhihu,
I'm sorry you are wronged.
Don't be.
I'm willing to do so.
It's good enough that
North Liang sacrificed me
in exchange for an ally.
I mean
the rumors about you and Liu Liting.
A bunch of people I don't know
defame me.
It has nothing to do with me.
I don't feel like
arguing with them at all.
His Highness won't misunderstand you.
I know.
He wants to
defend me against injustice.
They're just empty words.
Why should I believe you?
I can swear to God.
Can you compare to
such a powerful family
as Lu in Jiangnan?
Well...
I can't.
Then why did you pester Xu Zhihu?
Though she's a widow,
she is still a member of the Lu Family.
Weren't you afraid
the rumors about you and her
would offend the family?
Well...
Xu Zhihu is really beautiful.
So I'm attracted to her.
So
You risked your future for her?
Do you think I'll believe you?
Well...
You can't explain it clearly, can you?
I think
I'd better kill you.
What's your feud with North Liang?
You don't get to ask questions.
There're some things
I would never tell you
without knowing your identity.
It doesn't hurt to tell you.
I'm the princess of Chu.
The princess of West Chu?
You want me to walk around
being dressed like this?
Do you still want to walk around?
This is Mansion of Lu.
You'd better hide in the room.
You're overreacting.
Better than you get yourself killed.
Under my protection,
she won't get killed.
Thank you, sir.
I can rest assured with your protection.
Xu Fengnian asked me to protect you.
You should thank him, girl.
I would never thank him.
Old man.
Yes?
Where's my Divine Token?
I lent it to you.
Have you lost it?
Be quiet.
Xu Fengnian
borrowed it just now.
He has no rights
to borrow my dagger.
Why did he borrow it?
Do you recognize
the dagger?
The national dagger of West Chu,
Divine Token.
You know it.
According to historical records,
the dagger
may exchange for twelve cities.
I've heard of the precious dagger.
Are you really the princess of Chu?
Are you still alive?
Do you wish me to die?
I dare not.
Now I got it.
Xu Xiao conquered Chu.
Of course you hate them.
Please forgive me, Your Highness.
I heard that Xu Fengnian
is about to arrive at Jiangnan.
You showed up at this time.
It makes me confused.
I came to Jiangnan this time
in order to kill Xu Fengnian.
You're just extra points.
I...
I have the same goal as you.
I'm against North Liang, too.
Please wait a minute.
(To Liu Liting)
Look at this.
(From Jin Lanting at Imperial Academy)
Imperial Academy?
Was it from the capital?
A good friend of mine
is a scholar of Imperial Academy.
Was it his idea
to besmirch Xu Zhihu's reputation?
He said the court was always
wary of North Liang.
After North Liang
united with Jiangnan by marriage,
they became a sting in their heart.
If I blacken Xu Zhihu's name,
I may turn the Lu Family
against North Liang.
Though doing so
may offend the Lu Family,
in the end, I may be appreciated
by His Majesty.
When I go to the capital next time,
I'll get a limitless future.
Therefore,
it was a complete conspiracy.
Pestering Xu Zhihu
was just a smoke bomb.
Don't call it a conspiracy.
As a scholar,
it's my duty to serve my country.
Does she
know about these?
No, she doesn't.
What did you say?
Your wife happened to see you?
It wasn't a coincidence.
She specially went to look for me.
It wasn't a coincidence?
I have a message sent to my wife
before she hurried to Baoguo Temple.
Then you took advantage of
your wife's relative
and let the concubine in the palace
help you to publicize it,
so His Majesty
would hear of your name.
Liu Liting,
how could you trick your own wife?
I just followed the trend.
Don't say that.
Your Highness,
do you believe me now?
I have the same goal as you.
We're both against North Liang.
As for that,
you're right.
You're really vicious.
Xu Zhihu is ruined by you.
The Lu Family has strict rules.
In my opinion,
it's best if the Lu Family
exercise domestic discipline on her.
She may be beaten to death.
Unfortunately, Lu Baijie
has been protecting her.
It doesn't matter now.
We've got a chance.
What chance?
We should figure out
Xu Fengnian's schedule first.
Because of the rumors,
he would come to see me alone.
Then you take the opportunity
to kill him.
You can take revenge for your country.
As for me,
I can completely destroy
the oath of alliance forged
by the Lu Family and North Liang.
It satisfies both sides.
You're brilliant.
No wonder you're a scholar.
Who wrote the letter?
You...
Who are you?
Jin Lanting.
I've never heard of him.
There're many scholars
in Imperial Academy.
It's normal that you didn't hear of him.
I want to know who he works for.
Zhang Julu,
or someone else?
It's hard to decide.
He's got such devious means.
We must investigate him carefully later.
You did a great job just now,
but there was a flaw.
When he said he was under instructions
from the capital,
you shouldn't
soften your stance so quickly.
The people of Chu hate Xu Xiao,
but they hate the royal family
even more.
When he said his wife is related
to a concubine in the palace,
you should be tougher,
which fitted your role better.
I'm not
as thoughtful as you.
Who the hell are you?
I'm Xu Fengnian.
I heard you were going to kill me.
It doesn't matter, though.
But you've crossed my bottom line
trying to kill my sister
through the hands of the Lu Family.
You treat me with blades,
I'll return you with blades.
Liu Liting,
you've brought ruin
upon yourself.
Help!
Your Highness.
What about her?
She slapped my sister once.
My sister slapped her in return.
We're even with her.
Just let her go?
Why don't we kill her?
It's easy.
Whatever we do,
we shouldn't cross the bottom line.
Where are they going to take Mr. Liu?
What did he do?
What about his family?
We just tied them up.
We didn't hurt them.
Good.
Why do you shut his mouth?
Remove the gag.
Help!
The son of Lord of North Liang
is killing people!
- Just scream.
- Xu Fengnian.
Xu Fengnian dares to lynch people.
Is there any law in the country?
Is there any heavenly principle?
He's right.
I'm the son of Lord of North Liang, Xu Fengnian.
Everyone,
keep it in your mind.
Xu Fengnian,
you can't kill me.
Of course, I can kill you
if you try to kill other people.
It's the heavenly principle and justice.
I know I've made a mistake.
I'm willing to...
I'm willing to work for you.
You've lost your last bit of guts.
Go.
Get back to Yangcheng.
Xu Fengnian!
- Xu Fengnian, let go of me!
- It may kill him.
Xu Fengnian!
You won't die a natural death.
You just said
he was in danger in Reed Marshes.
Now God of Sword isn't around him.
He went to Jiangxin County
on the spur of the moment.
He won't be assassinated.
I'm not just worried about him.
With so many guards around him,
he was still attacked.
Huangman'er went to Mount Longhu alone.
It must be more dangerous.
With extraordinary power,
he can protect himself.
He is just human after all.
I thought in the first place
as long as I married into the Lu Family,
they would stay safely in North Liang.
I didn't expect us
to be far apart
from each other in the end.
Little buddy,
may I ask if this is Mount Longhu?
Yeah.
Which direction should I take
going up the mountain?
Thanks.
What are you looking at?
I'm waiting for the hawthorns.
Hawthorns?
When the hawthorns are ripe,
I'll save them for my brother.
Who is your brother?
Do you know him?
What's your family name?
Xu.
Oh.
Are you Xu Longxiang?
Yeah.
What a coincidence.
It probably is fate.
♪ The flower of pain ♪
♪ Blooms in my heart ♪
♪ I made a bet with the dawn ♪
♪ That you'll answer ♪
♪ Forgive this tragic end ♪
♪ Moved by the moment we met ♪
♪ In spite of thunder and lightning ♪
♪ In spite of my falling ♪
♪ When we are apart ♪
♪ I'll collapse ♪
♪ Capture an image of the memory ♪
♪ After all these ups and downs ♪
♪ The vanity ♪
♪ Who will open it again ♪
♪ It's worth it ♪
♪ It's enough ♪
♪ Drowned in sadness ♪
♪ Just to see through ♪
♪ I will whisper love to you ♪
♪ For a lifetime ♪
♪ End the worry in the world ♪
♪ It's worth it ♪
♪ I'll be there for you all my life ♪
♪ After the moments of beauty ♪
♪ You are my reason to be ♪
♪ If there is a way ♪
♪ To start over ♪
♪ Will you still remember me ♪